Tim Mendenhall

Email: timmendenhall@gmail.com Phone: (734) 619-0750

Summary

- Skilled Software Engineer with full stack development both on and off the web
- Foundation in many programming languages, databases, and cloud services
- Expertise in Javascript / Typescript and frameworks like React, React Native, and React Native Web
- Strong leadership skills focused on business needs from the development perspective

Technical Skills

Languages	Frameworks	Databases / Cloud	Version Control
JavaScript / Typescript	React / React Native	Microsoft	Git
C#	Node JS	SQL Server	Subversion
C / C++	Angular 1 / 2+		
Visual Basic	Babel	AWS	Team Foundation
PHP	Gulp	GCP	Server
Java (JSP)	Webpack	Azure	
HTML5	Karma		
CSS3	Jasmine	MongoDB, Firestore and other NoSQL	
	Jest	MySQL	

Professional Experience

Bounteous

September 2018 - Current

Lead Developer

- Helped estimate and develop client projects that utilize various technologies including: React, React Native, Angular
- Lead development teams on projects
- Set up the architecture and foundation for React Native / React Native Web projects that release on iOS, Android and web
- Worked closely with the client, experience design, QA, and developers to ensure projects were being delivered to the client's expectations

FlashRecruit

March 2016 - September 2018

Lead Software Engineer

- Split existing application structure into separate areas of concern such as: API, Web (client), iOS / Android Apps (client), and micro services for individual integrations such as Bullhorn and XML feed
- Recreated the existing application using React JS for reusable front end components and shared code with mobile applications
- Managed all front end web, api web, and database servers, SMS functionality, email functionality and DNS via Amazon Web Services
- Lead a small team from start through completion of the website redesign, API launch, iOS and Android app releases
- Multiple integrations with 3rd party systems via API including: Bullhorn, Broadbean, eQuest, job boards and XML feeds

MeridianRx

August 2015 - March 2016

Software Engineer (Contracted through Halo Group)

- Architected and created a front-end single page application solution for a Pharmacy Benefit Management (PBM) software system
- Implemented React JS for reusable front end components
- Utilized Node JS to serve files and manage packages with Node Package Manager (npm)
- Built the front end javascript and CSS (compiled from SASS) with Webpack
- Made use of new Ecmascript 6 or ES2015 features by using Babel to transpile down to Ecmascript
 5 code used by browsers
- Integrated Redux for unidirectional data flow and application state with isomorphic-fetch to integrate RESTful services for the application's persistent data

Optum, Inc., Detroit, MI

July 2013 - August 2015

Senior Web Developer and Technical Lead

- Consumed RESTful APIs via Angular JS
- Created core components for a health application portal used by all internal work streams using Adobe CQ5, JSP and Angular.JS
- Managed a team of over 10 javascript developers across multiple projects
- Lead a private health exchanges project from the development perspective, working with business leaders to estimate, plan and deliver the product that meets the clients needs

The Grand River, Inc., Ann Arbor, MI

June 2012 - July 2013

Web Developer

- Built back-end e-commerce solutions for large-scale clients using PHP and the Magento framework
- Created reusable Magento modules sold and used for multiple clients
- Converted client websites into Magento sites through data imports and exports, custom Magento theming and module integrations to manage payments, order tracking and analytics
- Developed and architected a learning management software solution using PHP, MySQL, and Concrete5 framework used for TGIF's internal employee training

Applied Systems, University Park, IL

October 2010 - June 2012

Software Developer

- Completed new functionality features within an enterprise insurance management software using Visual Basic .NET and transaction based MS SQL
- Assisted in software stabilization by fixing defects
- Created client SQL scripts used for imports, exports, patches and data cleanup
- Integrated MS Word dynamic documents with Visual Basic for Applications
- Developed automated scripts for end-to-end testing the software using an internally developed scripting language

Education

Devry University, Addison, IL

Graduated June 2009

B.S., Game and Simulation Programming

- GPA: 3.75
- Vice president of programming honors society, Epsilon Delta Phi